Synced and corrected by Aaronnmb www.addic7ed.com
傲骨之战 第一季 第二集
Bitch.
贱人
Fucking bitch.
天杀的贱人
I know where you live.
我知道你住哪里
I know where your family...
我知道你家人住哪...
This is for Maia Rindell.
我要告诉Maia Rindell
I'm gonna rape you and your dyke girl...
我会奸污你和你的同性女友...
Hi. Good morning.
早上好
And fuck you. You stole my money.
还有去你妈的 你窃取了我的财产
I just want you to hurt like I do.
我要让你体会我的痛苦
Hi, it's my first day here.
我是来报到的新职员
And, uh, I'm not too sure where to g...
我不知道去哪里报到...
_
Rindell骗局案
- Maia Rindell? - Yes!
- Maia Rindell吗 - 我是
You okay?
你没事吧
Yes! Just, um...
没事 只不过那个...
Hi.
你好
Julius Cain.
我是Julius Cain
I'm the managing partner here.
这里的合伙人
Let me show you to your desk.
我带你去办公地点
We have 55 associates and 40 work stations,
这里有55名律师 却只有40个工作台
so we employ a hot desk system.
所以办公桌非常吃紧
Occupy any empty chair in the communal area,
公共区域的空位随时会被占领
but keep your laptop with you because you might be returning
记得随身携带笔记本电脑 因为你回来的时候
to a different space when you come back.
你的位置可能就被占了
Go ahead.
就是这里
Good.
很好
At 10:00, I'm gonna need you at the SWSMU offices,
10点我要你去一趟SWSMU办公室
so meet me at reception in 20 minutes.
20分钟内来接待处找我
- The what? - SWSMU.
- 什么地方 - 仓库与商场销售人员工会
One of our union contracts.
我们的一个工会合同
Once a month, we offer their members
每个月我们都会给工会成员
pro bono service as part of our retainer.
提供一次无偿法律服务
20 minutes.
20分钟
_
我要强奸你 再把你们奶子割掉
Did you hear that, Diane?
你听清楚了吗 Diane
I... yes. I just can't believe it.
我...听清楚了 我只是不敢相信
They're withholding my capital contribution?
他们打算扣留我的认缴资本
They say they have to review your tenure.
他们还要复查你的任职
What tenure?! I was a name partner.
什么任职啊 我是冠名合伙人
I created that firm.
那间律所是我创立的
- It's my money. - I'm sorry, Diane.
- 那是我的财产 - 非常抱歉 Diane
Do I have any reserves?
我还有其他存款吗
If you sell your apartment.
除非你卖了你的公寓
I can't do that.
这我做不到
Well, you can always talk to your new partners,
你可以找你新合伙人谈谈
and see if they'll offer you a loan.
看他们是否能提供贷款
Ah, we tried to call you at home.
我们打电话到你家没人接
- Because? - We're moving you down the hall.
- 什么事 - 你得搬到楼下大厅
There's a new partner.
有新的合伙人要来了
We have to make room.
我们得腾出办公室
Diane?
Diane吗
Yep.
是的
See, it's not so bad.
你看 也不算太差
Home sweet home.
多温馨的地方啊
Oh, and I'm gonna need you at the SWSMU this morning.
我要你今天去一趟SWSMU
Why? I did it last month.
为什么 我上个月去过了
Yes, and you were so good at it, too.
对啊 你的表现非常好
Good morning.
早上好
Sharise.
Sharise
Come on, come get this.
来啊 来接啊
Come get this. Come get this!
来接着啊 来吧
How that college search coming?
大学挑选进展如何啦
Ah, all-consuming. Twins, you know.
正全力投入呢 双胞胎呢 你知道的
Yeah, I hear you.
好的 我知道了
Any word on the Kendall offer?
Kendall的案子进展如何
They called this morning.
他们今早来电话了
Who? David Lee?
谁 是David Lee吗
Yes, sir.
是的
We're getting our six mill.
六百万就快到手了
Diane here yet?
Diane来了吗
Yeah, she's in with Barbara.
来了 她在见Barbara
She is, huh?
来了就好
I heard you speak at an ABA conference a few years ago.
我听过你几年前在全美律师协会 会议上的发言
- Oh, yes. On racial hiring? - That's right.
- 关于种族雇佣的那次吗 - 正是
Oh, well, I hope I didn't embarrass myself too much.
希望我当时没有太献丑
Hmm, not too much.
没怎么献丑
Diane Lockhart.
Diane Lockhart
I feel like we acquired
我发现我们这里刚添了一员猛将
- Adrian, how are you? - Good, good.
- Adrian 你怎么样 - 很好 很好
A little gift for you.
这是见面礼
Spring Arbor Lake Wine,
泉亚伯湖之葡萄酒
my very own label, 2006. Mwah.
我自己产的 2006年的酒
You have a winery?
你有酿酒厂吗
Ah, just a row of vines, that's all. Sit, sit.
几串葡萄藤而已 请坐
So how's everything going with you two?
你们俩谈得怎么样啊
- Barbara give you the rundown? - She did.
- Barbara跟你介绍公司概况了吗 - 是的
Are you two playing nice?
你们相处愉快吗
- We are, Adrian. - Good.
- 非常愉快 Adrian - 那就好
Oh, by the way, just a housekeeping matter,
顺便说一句 不是什么大事
but we'll need your capital contribution by next week.
但下周需要你的认缴资本
Oh, yes, of course.
是的 当然
Um, just so you know,
你知道的
my old firm is being a bit intransigent.
我之前的律所有点不肯放手
Yeah, David Lee.
是的 那个David Lee
- Wonderful guy. - So, um,
- 那个大好人 - 所以呢
if you don't mind being a bit patient.
能否宽限一段时间
Of course.
当然可以
But listen, I'll need you in the 11:00 a.m. meeting
但是听着 一会儿11点来和诉讼投资人开会
to pitch cases to our litigation financiers.
商讨案件挑选
Right.
好的
- Well, good. I'll see you there. - You will.
- 到时见 - 好的
Diane.
Diane
- Welcome. - Thank you.
- 欢迎加入 - 谢谢
And how patient are we to be?
我们要宽限多久
Let's give her two weeks.
给她两周的时间
- Hello? - Just plugging in your computer.
- 你好吗 - 在帮你接电脑插头
Are you from Lockhart, Deckler?
你是Lockhart&Deckler律所的人吗
Lee, Lyman, Deckler, Gussman...
还有Lee&Lyman&Deckler&Gussman
Well, that didn't take them very long.
改名动作倒挺快的
I know. Bunch of assholes.
我知道 一群人渣
- Marissa? - Yeah, hey.
- Marissa - 是啊 你好
Want me to set up anything else?
还需要我布置什么吗
- No, I can do it. - No, let me.
- 不 我自己来 - 别 还是让我来吧
If I get back too quick,
如果太早回去
they'll just send me out on another errand.
他们会给我安排其他差事
Here, I'll hang these.
我来把这些东西挂起来
When Alicia hired me,
当初Alicia雇佣我的时候
I was supposed to be involved in cases and everything,
我应该是忙活案子之类的事情
but it's been all moving boxes since she left.
自她离开后 我就只是当苦力
Still want this?
要留起来吗
Definitely.
当然
And, uh, where do you want these?
你打算摆哪里
- What are those? - African masks.
- 这些是什么 - 非洲土著面具
Well, I can see that. Where are they from?
我看得出来 但哪里来的
Your office.
你办公室
No.
不是
David Lee. Very funny.
David Lee 真有意思
By the way, I know you still need an assistant, Diane.
还有 我知道你需要一位助手 Diane
- Hello. - Uh, this is Marissa,
- 你好 - 这是Marissa
from my old firm.
来自我之前的律所
Hi. Just dropping stuff off.
我只是送东西过来
Well, I have a few people coming in today
今天几个人来应聘助理
I'll send them by.
我会让他们过来的
Thank you.
谢谢
Okay, I don't want to sound self-serving here,
不是我自作主张
but I think it's a smart move for you to hire me.
但我建议你还是雇佣我为妙
Oh, good to know. Thank you.
好提议 谢谢
No, seriously. You need an assistant.
不 说真的 你的确需要助理
I can do whatever you want around here,
我可以随时听你差遣
and I'm not that expensive. What are you paying?
而且我也不贵 开个价吧
Why don't you just leave your résumé, Marissa?
请留下你的简历 Marissa
I don't have one. I'm much better in person, anyway.
我没有简历 我本人能说明一切
Look, just hire me for one day,
哪怕只雇佣我一天
just until you get someone better.
直到你找到更合适的人选
And I promise you won't get someone better.
但我保证没人比我更适合
You limit your pro bono consultations
你们的无偿咨询不得超过20分钟
If their legal issues require more time, go to Lucca.
如果他们的法律问题耗时过长 就去找Lucca
She will sign off on more time.
她会签字同意延时
Remember, you're only here
记住 你们来这里
to offer legal advice, not legal work.
是提供法律咨询 不是律师工作
Don't get tied down.
别把自己困住
Move people on into other
尽量把群众分流到其它地方
Prairie State or Legal Assistance.
比如伊利诺斯州 或者法律援助
You're the "door close" button in the elevator.
你们是电梯里的关门按钮
Comforting, but not necessarily effective.
是心理慰藉 不一定要产生作用
Here we go.
去吧
Okay, members, listen up, listen up.
诸位 听好了 听好
Remember these lawyers are here as union advocates,
这些人是工会的代表律师
so please limit your questions to workplace matters.
只能咨询与工作有关的法律问题
Only workplace matters.
仅限工作的法律问题
Okay, who is here on their work break, please raise your hand.
处于工作空闲时间的人请举手
Oh, come on.
拜托
Donny, I know it's your day off. Get your hand down.
Donny 我知道你今天休假 把手放下
Only people on their lunch break.
咨询仅限处于午休时间的人
Come on, you're only screwing over
别这样 你们是在给工会的兄弟姐妹添乱
Good.
很好
Those on lunch break, come on up to the stage.
午休的人请来到台上
Line up for each desk. Let's go.
排成一队等待咨询 快点
You're seriously telling me I have to go to someone else
午休时间本就不多 你还让我去找别人吗
The thing is, ma'am, we're not really here
重点是 女士 我们来这里
to help with family law issues,
不是帮助解决家庭法律问题
but, uh, I can refer you to...
但是我可以介绍你去...
He's not paying child support!
他不肯支付孩子抚养费
How am I supposed to make ends meet if he won't pay child support?
如果他不支付抚养费 我要怎么维持开销
I know, I'm sorry. It's just...
我知道 抱歉 只是...
Well, I'm not really supposed to help with...
我来这里不是为了...
Then why are you here?
那你来这里干嘛
If you can't help, why are you here?
如果你无法提供帮助 你来干嘛
I need help.
我需要帮助
Hello.
你好
Oh, come on.
不会吧
I'm gonna help you out here.
我来帮你减轻负担吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Sir, would you like to come to my desk?
先生 你愿意来我这里咨询吗
No, I'm good here.
不了 这里还不错
I'm a third-year associate. She just passed the bar.
我有三年律师资历 她只是新人
That's okay.
没事
I'm sticking.
就这样吧
Next?
你呢
I, I just can't survive on $400 a week.
一周400美金根本不够用
I can't pay for my rent.
我无力支付租金
I can't pay for my ex-wife.
我无力支付前妻赡养费
And they're not adjusting it for after taxes.
他们也没按照税后标准收入来调整发薪
They're just taking it right off the top.
只是按总收入直接扣除
I-I'm sorry, I don't understand.
抱歉 我不明白了
You're... you're being paid $400 a week?
你每周获取400美金吗
Yeah.
是啊
Wait, no.
等一下 不是
And my rent is twice that. Okay?
我的租金是所得的两倍 好吗
- Do you need to get that? - No.
- 你要不要看一下短信 - 不
- Uh, no. It does that. - _
不 不管它
Yeah, mine, too.
我也是
You know, I used to get some good news,
我以前一切顺风顺水
but now I feel like it's all bad.
但现在我感到诸事不顺
I don't even like answering it nowadays.
我如今甚至都不想与人交谈
So, um, I'm sorry,
所以 抱歉
I'm, I'm not too sure
我不太明白
how they were able to lower your salary.
他们怎么会降低你的薪水
Not lower. Garnish.
不是降低 而是克扣
They're saying that I stole 400 running shoes.
他们说我偷了400双跑鞋
- What? 400 running shoes? - Yeah.
- 什么 400双跑鞋 - 是的
And they say that's $70,000, but that's retail,
他们说价值7万美金 但那是零售
and they don't pay retail. They just pay wholesale,
他们又并不按照零售价售卖 只是批发价
- so it should be half that. - Wait, I'm sorry.
- 所以就应该只有一半 - 等等 抱歉
Could-could you start again?
你能从头再说一遍吗
Okay.
好的
- BMI... - Mm-hmm.
BMI商店...
... my store says that I stole 400 running shoes.
我工作的商铺控诉我偷了400双跑鞋
And did you?
你偷了吗
No, I've never stolen anything in my entire life.
没有 我这一生没偷过任何东西
But they're garnishing my wages for the retail amount,
他们以零售额来克扣我的工资
and it should be the wholesale amount.
实际应该按照批发价
That's double what I should pay!
这让我赔了一倍啊
But if you didn't steal anything,
但如果你没有偷东西的话
why are you letting them garnish your wages at all?
你为什么让他们克扣你的工资呢
Because I signed a confession.
因为我签字认罪了
I don't understand. Why did he confess?
我不明白他为何要认罪
They pressured him to.
他们胁迫他的
They threatened to fire him if he didn't.
他们威胁如果他不签字 就解雇他
He just wants them to charge him
他只是想让他们用批发价扣
the wholesale amount and not the retail amount.
而不是零售价
And he wants to go to arbitration for that?
他愿意为此申请仲裁吗
Well, his contract requires that he go to arbitration.
他的合约需要他申请仲裁
But he wants me to represent him.
但他希望我当代理律师
I just need you to sign me off
我只要你同意我延时2小时
You know this is just pro bono?
你知道这是无偿服务
Right? It's a goodwill gesture.
对吧 只是表达善意
- We're not here to right a wrong. - No, I know, but...
- 我们不是来伸张正义 - 是的 我知道 不过...
it's only two hours work.
只是两小时的事情
I want to do it.
我想去做
When's the arbitration?
仲裁是什么时候
This afternoon.
今天下午
Okay.
好的
Good luck.
祝你好运
Everything good with you?
你最近都还顺利吗
Yeah.
还行吧
Yeah, for the first time in a while... yes.
很久以来第一次觉得 还行
It's good when you can focus on someone else's problem.
当你专注于别人的问题时 情况就会好转
First place I've been I wasn't recognized.
这是我第一次 没被人认出来然后痛骂
This is our highest priority case.
这是我们优先处理的案子
It's a hanging in a jail cell... Holly Orlin.
在牢房里上吊了... Holly Orlin
You'll find a Chicago Tribune article on top there.
资料上有芝加哥论坛报的报道
This is the worst Cook County jail abuse
这是我所见以来库克县
I have seen in years.
最严重的监狱霸凌
So, we're suing for $12 million,
所以我们索赔1200万
but we do expect settlement before trial.
但要在庭审前和解赔偿
- Any videotape? - No.
- 有录像资料吗 - 没有
But we have a very sympathetic family
但我们有令人同情的受害者家庭
and a grieving widower.
和悲伤的鳏夫
So, all we need of your financing is $300 thousand.
所以我们需要你们的集资 是30万美金
- Mm-mm. - No. Thanks, though.
即便如此 不了 谢谢
Our algorithm is going cool on police suits.
我们的原则是不介入警方诉讼
You sure about that?
你确定吗
Mm-hmm. What else?
还有其它事吗
Well, I think that, uh, Diane, our newest partner...
我认为 Diane 我们的新合伙人...
she just joined us from Lockhart, Deckler & Gussman...
她刚从Lockhart&Deckler&Gussman 律所跳槽过来...
can speak to a new case.
她有个新案子
Uh, we've been looking into parole abuses.
我们在调查滥用假释职权
Some parolees have been rejected
部分犯人因为某些报复性原因
for, uh, punitive reasons.
被拒绝假释
I think my partner worries there's no money there.
我的同事认为此案没有太多利益
That depends on how vulnerable the State feels.
这取决于政府对此危机感多重
No. It depends on the trend.
不是 这取决于大趋势
The trend is against you.
而这趋势对你不利
Look, now we understand you have your little algebraic spells,
我明白你有点代数分析天赋
but we understand the system.
但我们更了解体制
And you'll get ten percent of our earnings.
我们的收益 你百分之十的分成
Why don't you let us help you make some money?
为何不让我们共谋利益
What else have you got?
你们还有什么案子
- Malpractice? - Mm-hmm.
医疗事故
It's a malpractice suit.
有份失职诉讼
- Uh, excuse me. - Yeah.
- 失陪 - 没事
- Second page. - What's wrong?
- 第二页 - 什么事
Someone here to see you. Lenore Rindell.
有人想见你 Lenore Rindell
- Where? - In your office.
- 她在哪 - 在你办公室
You want me to get rid of her?
想让我撵走她吗
What do you need, Lenore?
找我什么事 Lenore
- I-I came to see Maia. - She's out.
- 我来看看Maia - 她不在
She's not talking to me, she's not answering my calls.
她不和我说话 也不回我电话
My guess is her lawyer told her not to.
我猜是她的律师让她这么做的
Can you talk to her, Diane? Please.
你能劝劝她吗 Diane 求你了
No.
不行
Why?
为什么
I don't know what bubble you're living in, Lenore,
你是活在童话故事里吗
but you do see my office here?
你看见了吧 我的办公室
You do see that I am not retired,
我现在还没有退休
that I am still working.
还在工作
This wasn't us. This was Jax.
这不怪我们 是Jax
This is his Ponzi scheme, not ours...
他玩的庞氏骗局 不是我们
You want to have an honest conversation here, then let's have it.
你想要坦诚地聊一聊吗 来吧
I came to you last week and asked for my money back,
我上周去找你 想把我的钱要回来
so that I could buy my dream house, and what did you say?
那样我就可以买到我梦寐以求的房子 你是怎么说的
- We didn't... - No, I want to hear you say it.
- 我们没有... - 不 我要听你再说一遍
- What did you say? - This wasn't us.
- 你说了什么 - 这真的不怪我们
You said keep it in your account, and borrow on it.
你说别动存款 去贷款吧
I could've had my money back.
我本来可以拿回我的钱
I...
我...
I think it's a good idea that you go.
你现在最好是离开
Diane, look at me.
Diane 看着我
I'm innocent.
我是无辜的
Henry's innocent.
Henry也是无辜的
You are a defense lawyer.
你是个辩护律师
Why can't you extend us the same courtesy
为什么不能像对待其他委托人一样
you do your other clients?
对待我们呢
We are wrongly accused.
我们是被诬陷的
Just because the Feds say it
不能调查局说什么
doesn't make it true.
你就信什么
I'll tell Maia that you dropped by.
我会跟Maia说你来过
I know I shouldn't ask this, but...
我知道我的请求有些过分
Henry needs your help.
但是Henry需要你的帮助
He's in jail and no one will visit him.
他在牢里 没有人去探望他
His lawyer's advising him to plead guilty,
他的律师让他认罪
but I don't think he should.
但我觉得不该这么做
He's your oldest friend, Diane.
他是你的至交 Diane
Will you talk to him?
你能和他谈谈吗
So it's like a trial?
这和庭审差不多吧
Yes, just answer honestly.
是的 如实回答就好
That's all you have to do.
你要做的就是这个
And if I lose?
如果我输了呢
Well, there's no appeal, so...
没有上诉的机会 所以
if you lose, you lose.
如果输了就是输了
Frank Gwinn.
Frank Gwinn
Here.
到
Go ahead. You're the lawyer?
去吧 你是律师吗
Uh, yes, from Reddick, Boseman &...
是的 来自Reddick&Boseman&...
- Good, I'm the arbiter. - ... Kolstad...
- 好 我是仲裁人 - ... Kolstad律所...
Let's hear it.
开始吧
And this is Benji Diyardian
这位是Benji Diyardian
from BMI's loss-prevention department.
BMI防损部门的
He questioned me.
是他审问的我
- Let's hear it. - I...
- 开始吧 - 我...
Good afternoon.
下午好
Frank's employer, BMI,
Frank的雇主 BMI
a sporting good store with $12 billion in assets
是一家拥有120亿资产的体育用品百货
and franchises throughout the country...
在全国各地都有经销权
Yeah, I-I don't need that.
我不需要这些
Right. Um...
好的
They have accused my client of stealing
BMI指控我的当事人
400 running shoes from their back-stock.
声称他在库存里偷了400双跑鞋
- 417. - Objection.
- 417双 - 反对
Okay, um,
好吧
- and he didn't do it, right? - Uh, that is correct, sir.
- 所以他没偷对吧 - 没错 先生
He did not do it.
他没有偷
What do you need, ma'am?
什么事 女士
I'm here as an observer for the union.
我是工会指派的观察员
Why?
为什么
We just want to make sure everything's fair.
我们只是想要确保一切公平
Okay, keep going, miss.
好吧 继续
My client did not steal any shoes.
我的当事人没有偷任何东西
He has no record and yet the company, BMI,
他没有前科 但BMI公司
have chosen to garnish his salary by almost 40%.
却仍选择榨取他近40%的工资
We didn't garnish anything, he confessed.
不存在这个说法 他承认他偷了
No, excuse me, sir, you'll have your chance.
不好意思 会轮到你说的
Um, this is a massive,
这是一家资产12亿的
$12 billion company
大型百货公司
stealing half my client's pay.
窃取员工近一半工资的案子
Stealing, really? We have his confession on the record.
窃取 是吗 我们有他认罪的记录
No, he was forced to confess.
他是被迫的
- He was told if he did not confess... - He was not told anything.
- 他被告知 如果他不承认... - 我们没有强迫他做任何事
If he did not confess, then he would be fired.
如果他不承认 他就会被解雇
Frank, how long did this man question you?
Frank 这个人审问了你多久
- Seven hours. - Without break.
- 7个小时 - 没有间断
He was told he could not leave the room.
他被强制关在房间里
Only because he's an employee and he was on the clock.
这只是因为他是员工 而且他在当班
Let me see the confession.
让我看一下供词
Would the union rep like to see it, too?
工会代表你要看看吗
Uh, I would, thank you.
好的 谢谢
Mr. Arbiter, as you read that, please remember
仲裁人先生 请记住
that he was forced to sign that confession.
他是被迫在供词上签字的
I never forced anyone. This is the Friedman method.
我没强迫他 这是弗里德曼审问法
- I never diverged once from it at all. - The what?
- 我是照着这个方法审的 没有出格的 - 什么
The Friedman method, it's a process of questioning
弗里德曼法 这是一个质询方法
I was trained and certified in.
我受过培训也得到了认证
Sir,
先生
is this your signature?
这是你的签名吗
Yes.
是的
Then in exercise of powers conferred under Clause 25
根据双方达成的
of the agreement entered into between the parties,
条款中的第25项
judgment is made in favor of the respondent.
被告胜诉
Wait, w-what? What, that's it?
等等 什么 这就完了
Thank you, I'll see the next arbitration.
谢谢 我要审下一个案子了
- But he didn't do it! - I'll see the next arbitration.
- 他没有偷 - 下一个
False imprisonment.
非法监禁
Mr. Arbiter, we ask that the arbitration...
仲裁人先生 我们请求
be reopened...
再次仲裁
based on the matter of false imprisonment.
基于我的当事人遭受非法监禁
- Oh, come on... - My client was held
- 拜托 - 我的委托人被强制
against his will for seven hours,
关押近7个小时
in direct contravention of... everything.
这直接违反了...所有法律
The issue of false imprisonment is irrelevant.
这案子和非法监禁无关
Judgment is again made in favor of the respondent.
再次宣判 被告胜诉
That's not your decision to make, sir.
这就不是你能定夺的了 先生
Excuse me?
什么
The arbitration agreement with Ms. Rindell's client
Rindell女士的当事人仲裁协议
does not cover tort claims.
不包括民事侵权索赔
And false imprisonment is a tort claim.
但是非法监禁就是一项民事侵权索赔
- Then we are stalemated. - No, we're not.
- 这就陷入僵局了 - 不 并没有
- And why is that? - Because we'll see you in court.
- 怎么会呢 - 因为我们会法庭上见
Henry.
Henry
How are you?
你还好吗
Rupert tells me I should accept a guilty plea.
Rupert让我接受认罪协议
20 years.
20年
What do you think?
你怎么看
I think this is bad, Hank.
这么做不明智 Hank
Yeah, you and I, Diane,
你和我 Diane
we always told each other the truth.
我们总是坦诚相待
No matter where... in college, after,
无论何时何地 大学时期 毕业以后
before Lenore.
在Lenore面前
And I'm telling you the truth now.
现在我说的是事实
I did not do this.
不是我做的
Hank, what am I supposed to do with that?
Hank 你想让我怎么做
I am bankrupted, completely.
我破产了 倾家荡产
Two months ago, I hired a forensics accountant
两个月前 我请了一位法务会计
to look into Jax's trades.
调查了Jax的交易
There was $83 million missing.
有8300万美元的下落不明
The accountant found Jax had moved the money
会计发现Jax把钱
into his private account.
挪到了他自己的名下
I tried to confront him, but before I could,
我本想试着和他对质 在那之前
Jax went to the Feds to turn me in.
他抢先告发了我
You should be telling this to your lawyer, not to me.
这应该说给你的律师听 而不是我
I did, but Rupert said it doesn't matter.
我说过了 但Rupert说这是螳臂当车
There are too many bad facts.
有太多不利因素指向我了
Okay.
好吧
Let me look into another lawyer.
我去找其他律师吧
- Why not you? - No.
- 为什么你不可以 - 不行
You need someone objective.
我怕我会感情用事
How's Maia?
Maia最近如何
- She's doing well. - Good.
- 她上手很快 - 很好
She's on a case.
她已经开始接案子了
She's gonna blow us all away.
她会让我们骄傲的
Did she see her mom?
她去看她妈妈了吗
No.
没有
I think it's best that she stay away
我觉得等一切重回正轨之后再去
until all this gets straightened out.
是最明智的
But that could be years.
那可能要花上好几年
I know.
是的
Lenore didn't tell you?
Lenore告诉你了吗
Tell me what?
告诉我什么
She doesn't have years.
她时间不多了
Her breast cancer, it's back.
她的乳腺癌复发了
Spread to her lymph nodes.
癌细胞扩散到她的淋巴结
Maybe I should go see her.
或许我应该去看看她
I'd talk to your lawyer first.
要是我 我会先联系你的律师
You don't think I should go see her?
你认为我不该去看望她吗
No, it's just...
不 只是...
I think you should be careful.
我觉得你要小心行事
She misunderstood my intent, or she ignored it,
她误解了我的意图 或者说她根本没当回事
but we just don't have time for this.
但是现在我们没有时间了
and we raise expectations
我们对律所的作为
for what our firm can do!
有更高的期待
Ah, Lucca.
Lucca
It seems we picked up a new case this morning.
我们今早好像接了新的案子
I told you we didn't want to get tangled up in small-ball litigation.
我说过了我们不想在小案子上纠缠
This is not small-ball.
这个案子不小
BMI has $12 billion in assets...
BMI有近120亿资产
Yes, and there won't be any punitive damages here.
没错 但是拿不到任何惩罚性赔偿
- But we don't know that. - We do know that.
- 这不一定 - 这是肯定的
This is one union member,
只有一个工会成员
and we're about to put in 40 billable hours,
我们要花40个计费时数
to get him what, $20,000 in back pay?
给他争取些什么 两万美元的欠薪
Is this about you losing your office to a partner?
你是因为把办公室让给合伙人 受刺激了吗
No.
不
This is about a good case.
这是个好案子
Hey, do you know what the Friedman Method is?
你知道弗里德曼法吗
The Friedman Method?
弗里德曼法吗
Yeah, it's a way to interrogate a suspect... why?
知道 这是审问嫌疑人的一种方法 怎么了
It's a case I'm on.
这和我接的案子有关
How do I find out more about it?
怎么做才可以了解更多
Easily, they have seminars.
很简单 他们有培训班
Just look them up online.
上网查
You pay the money, and you, too,
只要交钱报名 你也可以
can learn how to be a cop.
学习怎么当警察
Good to know.
太好了
Oh, okay. I got to go, bye.
好了 我得挂了 拜拜
- We're being shut down. - What?
- 我们不让接了 - 什么
They're worried the case is too small.
他们担心这个案子太小
You're kidding.
开玩笑吧
I was just about to sign up for a Friedman seminar
我刚准备报名弗里德曼培训班
to find out more.
打算多了解点
You know what, do it anyway.
这样吧 你报名吧
It's on our time.
反正花的是我们自己的时间
Why not?
为什么不呢
Okay.
好的
People lie.
人会说谎
And when people lie, they want to confess...
而当他们说谎时 他们会想坦白
it's human nature.
这是人的本性
Your job... you and you and you...
你需要做的...你...你...还有你
is to enable that process.
就是去触发坦白动机
You are a crucial step to their cleansing.
你们起到了关键作用
What you will learn over the next four sessions
后面的四节课你们将会学到
is the Friedman method.
弗里德曼法
A way to determine guilt...
一个确认罪行
and obtain a confession.
并且让罪犯供认的方法
One of these four people is lying.
这四个人中有一位在说谎
They all deny taking money from a cash register,
他们都否认自己从收银台里拿了钱
but one of them did.
但有一位确实拿了
The first step in the Friedman Method is
弗里德曼法的第一步就是
ascertain guilt.
确认罪行
Find out who is lying.
找出说谎的人
Look, I didn't do it.
听着 我没有偷钱
I wasn't even there. That's the truth.
我当时都不在场 这是实话
Pretty convincing, huh?
很有说服力 对吧
But ignore the words. They're irrelevant.
但是不要管他们说什么 这和他们是否有罪并无关联
Everybody swears they're innocent,
每个人都发誓自己是无辜的
but no one can hide their face.
但没人可以掩饰自己的脸
No one can hide their expressions.
没人可能掩饰自己的表情
The most important thing is to get the suspect to look right at you
最重要的是让嫌疑人直视你的眼睛
and repeat the statement over and over.
一遍遍地重复他们的陈述
Let's watch it again.
我们再来看一遍
I'm going to slow down the image.
我会放慢播放速度
Look, I didn't do it.
听着 我没有偷钱
I wasn't even there...
我当时根本不在场
- That's the truth... - There!
- 这是实话 - 那里
Right there. See? Under his lip?
就在那里 看到了吗 在他的嘴唇下方
The risorius muscle.
他的笑肌
It's part of the expression of fear.
害怕的表情是通过这部分肌肉表现的
When we are experiencing anxiety,
当我们处于焦虑状态
the risorius muscle will become tense.
笑肌会变得紧张
Look for it.
再来看看
I wasn't even there.
我当时根本不在那
- That's the truth. - See?
- 是真的 - 看见了吗
Clenched muscle.
肌肉收紧了
Good. Another telltale sign of anxiety, the forehead.
好 还有一个焦虑的迹象 额头
When there is a burst of anxiety,
当陷入严重紧张焦虑时
these muscles will tighten up,
这些肌肉会紧绷
the eyebrows will rise upward,
眉毛会上扬
only for a second... see?
时间很短 看到了吗
The liar wants to force his expressions
说谎的人想要控制住表情
to look relaxed, in control.
以显镇定
Therefore, the expression you're looking for
所以 你要找的表情
is fleeting, momentary.
是短暂的 瞬间的事
Do you think that's true,
你觉得这个方法说得过去吗
the way to discover a liar?
识破谎言的办法
No, it's bad psychology.
这是拙劣的心理学
How do you mean?
怎么说
"Ignore the words"?
"别管他说了什么"
Seriously?
没开玩笑吧
How does someone prove their innocence
不解释自己无罪
without explaining why they're innocent?
要怎么证明自己的清白
And he says it's all about detecting anxiety.
他说这一切都在于观察疑犯的紧张
Well, I don't care how innocent you are,
先不管你是不是清白的
if a cop calls you in for questioning,
要是被警察带去审讯
you're gonna be anxious.
你肯定会紧张
So what does anxiety prove?
那紧张能说明什么呢
What if there is no cop?
那如果没有警察呢
What if there is no reason to be anxious?
如果在没有理由紧张的情况下呢
I don't know. Everybody's different.
我不清楚 每个人都不一样
Everybody's got their tell. I don't...
每个人都有自己的马脚 我不知道...
What?
怎么了
This isn't a small thing.
这不是件小事
This is a massive class action.
这是一起庞大的集体诉讼
Every multi-billion dollar nationwide retailer
每个资产过十亿的全国连锁零销商
is sending middle-management to these seminars...
都派中层管理去参加培训会
East Wing Running Shoes, Widespread Tech, B&X...
东翼跑鞋 广科百货 拳击百货...
I thought these seminars were about training cops.
我以为这些培训是针对警察的
That's how they were intended,
这是他们的初衷
but retail stores are using the same techniques
但是零销商把这个方法
against their own employees,
用在了自己的员工身上
and it's just as likely to result in a false positive.
结果很可能会出现偏差
Barbara, what do you think?
Barbara 你怎么看
It's good.
挺好
Go certify a class.
那去找共同诉讼人吧
We should put Bobby on it with her.
我们应该让Bobby和她一起
It's a big thing now.
这现在是个大案子了
- Who's on it with her right now? - The new associate, Maia.
- 现在谁在和她跟进这案子 - 一个新来的 叫Maia
I'd keep her on it. Maia's good.
那就让她继续 Maia不错
And she's motivated.
而且她很有干劲
- That Rindell kid? - Yes.
- Rindell家的孩子吗 - 是啊
Sure. Everybody hates her.
没错 大家都讨厌她
Great way to mold a fighter.
但这也会促使她奋起
All right.
好吧
There may not even be a job here.
我就是想提醒你们一小下下
I just want to warn you.
这个位置可能根本不招人了
Uh, you're here for the assistant position?
你是来应聘做助手的吗
Come on in... Daniela?
进来吧 你是Daniela吧
Have a seat.
请坐吧
This is still your case, Frank,
Frank 这还是你的案子
but it's also now a class action.
但这现在也是一桩共同诉讼案了
- So I don't pay anything? - Right.
- 那我现在不用付任何费用了吗 - 没错
And it's more likely that you'll get a larger settlement,
而且你很有可能得到更多赔偿
because these big companies will want to avoid the embarrassment.
因为这些大公司也不想被爆出这种丑闻
Is this going to move quickly now, because I'm having trouble paying rent.
但是得快点 因为我要还不起房租了
We think the companies will try to win this motion to dismiss.
我想这些公司会为了打赢官司而申请驳回起诉
And if not, they'll negotiate a settlement.
但要是没有 他们也会协商解决办法
- All right, do I have to sign something? - Yes.
- 好吧 那我现在需要签什么文件吗 - 需要
And, actually, you can help us, Frank.
而且实际上 Frank 你可以帮我们
We're looking for other workers
我们正在找和你一样
who have had their wages garnished, just like you.
被盘剥工资的员工
- So, if you... - What is this case again?
- 所以 要是你 - 这是啥案子来着
We're gathering a class of retail workers
我们在找一些零售商的员工
who were wrongly accused of stealing from their stores.
他们被指控监守自盗
Okay, got it.
好的 知道了
So are you coming back to work?
那你还回来工作吗
Everybody misses you.
大家都很想你
No, I got another job.
不了 我找到别的工作了
In fact, can you help me out with it?
你能帮我个忙吗
You know everybody around here.
这里所有人你都认识
Is there anybody in the mall who had their wages cut?
你知不知道这商场里谁的工资被削减了
We're bringing a lawsuit against all these big asshole companies,
我在代理一个被告是周扒皮公司们的案件
and I know you know all the people here and how they complain.
我知道你在这里是个百事通
So is anybody bitching about their paychecks?
所以你这有没有人抱怨过自己的工资呢
It's about people being forced to confess
就是关于工人们被迫承认
that they stole clothing or shoes or computers.
自己偷了衣服 鞋子 或是电脑
So if you hear anything from anybody, here's my card.
假设你从谁那听说了什么类似的事
Tell them to call me.
这是我的名片 请他们打给我
What the hell are you doing, Barbara?
你在搞什么啊 Barbara
What am I doing? I'm having a sandwich.
我在干嘛 我正在吃三明治
You're dragging my members into a class action.
你把我的成员牵连进一起共同诉讼案
If this is about the salary garnishing, we're not drag...
如果你是为克扣薪水而来 我们没有
You're pissing off management!
你惹恼了管理层
We're on the eve of a contract negotiation,
我们面临合同谈判
and you're pissing off management.
但你竟然惹怒管理层
It was a union-member complaint.
这是联合起来的成员们的起诉
- We are merely... - No, no, no, no.
- 我们不过是 - 不不不
You convinced him to pursue a class action,
你们说服他提起共同诉讼
because you wanted the money.
因为你们自己想赚钱
You came into our offices and asked for our help
你们来我们办公室来寻求帮助
to collect a class...
说要找一些
Those two did.
就是那两个人
- Your contract is with us. - Yes.
- 你和我们签了合同 - 是
And you employed us to help your members and...
雇我们来帮助你们的成员
As a gesture, merely.
就是装装样子
Uh, maybe your members would like to know that.
你们的成员也许很想听听你的说辞
Seriously?
你认真的吗
That's how little our contract means to you?
合同对于你们来说毫无意义是吗
- You're threatening me? - God,
- 你在威胁我吗 - 天啊
if that's considered a threat, friend,
朋友 要是这在你听来都是威胁
I would love to live in your world.
那我真想住到你的世界里
We won't pay a cent for this class action,
这起共同诉讼我们一分钱都不会赞助
and we won't help in any way. So drop it.
也不会有任何形式的帮助 所以放弃吧
What are you gonna do?
那你怎么办
We're gonna find another benefactor.
我们另找赞助者
So what do you have?
你手里还有什么案子
A new suit. Very last-minute.
一个新案子 新鲜出炉
Class action against 12 nationwide retailers.
起诉12家国内零售商的共同诉讼
- I'll need financing on, say, 140... - How many in the class?
- 我需要赞助 大概 140 - 原告有多少人
We're gathering that as we speak,
和你们谈的同时 我们正在召集
but we think 20, maybe more.
但是肯定有20个人 甚至更多
Sympathetic, working-class families,
令人同情的 工薪阶层的家庭
all retail workers.
都是零售商的员工
Who's the test case?
有判例吗
Top of page three.
第三页上面
Frank Gwinn, 32 years old.
Frank Gwinn 32岁 离异父亲
Good witness. College-educated.
是个好证人 还受过高等教育
Worked at BMI selling shoes.
在BMI卖鞋
No litigation in his background, and no priors.
从没被起诉过 也没有前科
- Uh, he's delinquent on a loan. - It's a student loan.
- 他拖欠过贷款 - 那是学生贷款
2012. He's making payments again.
2012年的事了 现在他又接着还贷了
Your proposal?
你有什么建议吗
You finance 600 billable hours
你们赞助600个小时的有偿工时
for an initial payment of $300,000.
也就是3万美金
You'll have two exit ramps. One,
你有两条退路
after the motion to dismiss.
一是对方请求不予受理
Two, six months into trial,
二是六个月的审判程序
if we even go that long.
要是我们赢了
You share 40% of the award,
你将会得到我们收入的百分之四十
up to $8 million.
多达8百万美元
No.
不行
Why?
为什么
You can't get better.
你们的收益已经很丰厚了
Your motion to dismiss is in front of Judge Kevin Drago?
审理不予受理环节的法官是Kevin Drago吗
We've won in front of him before.
我们曾经赢过他审的案子
Our algorithm doesn't like him.
但是我们的算法不喜欢他
Not for this case.
至少是这个案子
Your algorithm's not taking into account
但你的算法没他妈把我是个好律师算进去
Don't swear, okay?
别爆粗成吗
It bugs out Jer.
会吓到Jer的
I'm sorry.
对不起
Does your algorithm even like this case?
那你的算法喜欢这个案子吗
It does.
那倒是很喜欢
Good optics, good potential pay-out.
有好的前景 回报收益也不错
It's just this judge.
关键是这个法官
It's okay, I will get you a new judge.
那行 我换个别的法官
- How you gonna do that? - I'm a good lawyer.
- 你怎么能说换就换 - 我是个好律师
We're going to court.
我们会上庭
Fuck the union, we will finance this thing ourselves.
去他妈的工会 咱们自己出钱
You, I want you in court.
你 我让你上庭辩护
Uh, uh, what is your name again?
你叫啥来着
- Maia. - Maia. Great.
- 我叫Maia - Maia 挺好
- Second chair. - I... well, thank you, sir.
- 我让你当副手 - 谢谢老板
Unfortunately we've run into a snag, Adrian.
遗憾的是我们正遇到瓶颈
- What? - The class.
- 什么 - 共同诉讼人
Without the union's help,
没有工会的帮助
we're having trouble locating employees
我们就没法找到被剥削工资的员工
Check crime reports.
查犯罪报道
Any business missing back-stock they'd report it, right?
他们不是会报道所有商场丢失库存事件吗
No. They tried that.
我们试过了 不行
Let's post fliers. Let's check Reddit.
那就发招募传单 上社交网站上查
Let's get creative.
多动动脑
I've told our financial partners
我都已经告诉赞助商
that we would have 20 members in the class,
咱们已经找来二十个共同诉讼人了
so let's get to it, all right?
所以咱们再努努力吧
Here's 23 employees who were accused of theft
这是23个被老板指控盗窃被减工资的员工
And I have feelers out to a dozen more.
我这还有十几个备选
And there are two more people here to be interviewed.
另外还有两个人来应聘助理
Who is that?
这是谁啊
My new assistant.
我的新助理
You want me to recuse myself?
你申请我回避是吗
Yes, Your Honor. Regretfully.
很遗憾是的 法官阁下
- You don't like me, Counselor? - No, I love you.
- 你是不喜欢我是吗 律师先生 - 并没有 我们都很敬重您
At our firm, we speak very highly of you all the time, Your Honor.
在我们律所大家都对法官大人您评价极高
But unfortunately, in this instance,
但遗憾的是 在本案中 我们有利益冲突
We're good here, Your Honor. No problem.
我们没有异议 法官阁下 没问题
Isn't this just a motion to dismiss?
这不是个申请驳回起诉案吗
I'm not sure how I can be conflicted out.
我确定没什么冲突
I've shopped at BMI, but that's about it.
我最多就是在BMI买过几双鞋 再没别的
And you, sir?
是吧 先生
Do I know you?
我认识你吗
No, Your Honor.
不认识 阁下
Nice try, Mr. Boseman,
Boseman先生 挺努力的
but I reject your motion to recuse me.
但我驳回你的回避申请
We can start with your first witness.
传你的第一个证人上庭吧
Actually, Your Honor, there's one more thing.
实际上 阁下 有个事儿
You're trying my patience, sir.
你在挑战我的耐性 先生
You recently you lost over a million dollars in an investment.
你最近在某项投资里损失了一百多万美元
- Am I correct? - That's none of your business.
- 我说的对吗 - 那也跟你没关系
And that loss has nothing to do with the matter here.
而且我的损失也跟本案无关
Now sit down.
好了你赶紧坐下吧
But unfortunately, our second chair here...
但遗憾的是 我们的这位副辩护律师
uh, Maia, would you stand up and state your full name please?
Maia 你能站起来把自己全名说出来吗
Maia Rindell.
Maia Rindell
As you can see, Your Honor,
正如您所看到的 法官大人
since you've lost most of your savings
正是因为您大部分积蓄都被Rindell庞氏案诈骗
you cannot fairly judge this case.
所以您无法公平公正的审判了
So here we all are on this lovely Wednesday afternoon.
在这个风和日丽的周三下午
And unfortunately,
不幸的是 我忘了带眼镜
So I will try to make do with these prescription sunglasses,
所以我得带着这副墨镜上庭
if you don't mind me looking a little bit like a movie star.
希望你们不要介意我看着像个影星似的
Very becoming, Your Honor.
和你很配 法官大人
Well, I wouldn't go that far.
我扯远了
Coming from L.A., I'm used to it.
我之前住洛杉矶 早都习惯了
Ah, Los Angeles.
天呐 洛杉矶
How is your drought?
你们那的旱情怎么样了
Uh, improving.
好多了
Good. I love the way your state
那太好了 我喜欢你们州 重视绿色能源
Yes, I have a Tesla myself.
是啊 我自己有辆特斯拉
It's such a wonderful car.
是辆好车
Your Honor, the motion to dismiss.
法官大人 驳回起诉案
Yes, thank you, Lucca.
是啊 谢谢你 Lucca
The simple fact is the plaintiff is attempting to use
本案的简明事实即
the theft of 400 running shoes from my client's...
原告试图用盗窃400双跑鞋一案
Not the theft. There is no theft here.
并不是盗窃 我们没有盗窃行为
If I could finish? Thank you.
能让我说完吗 谢谢你
To sue 15 respected companies.
起诉15家驰名公司
In other words, this is a Trojan Horse...
换句话说 这就像是特洛伊木马
Actually, the metaphor I would use, Your Honor,
事实上 要是我来比喻的话 法官大人
- is a reverse Robin Hood. - Seriously?
- 我会比作罗宾汉 - 你认真的吗
Well, this is getting heated.
辩论变的白热化了
My client makes $40,000 a year.
我的当事人年薪4万美元
Ms. Stevens' client makes $13 billion.
而Stevens女士的当事人每年入账130亿
And yet every payday, they take 40% of his take home pay.
却在每个发薪日盘剥我的当事人40%的薪水
Okay, well, battle lines drawn.
好了 你们的战线我看明白了
Ms. Stevens, your, your first witness.
Stevens女士 传唤你的第一个证人吧
We had a lot of theft from the store-room,
我们发生了多起仓库被偷事件
almost $600,000 this year.
光是今年损失就快达到60万美金
So I was asked to question the employees.
而我的职责是审讯雇员
And why did you zero in on the plaintiff?
那你是怎么盯上原告的呢
He showed signs of deception per the Friedman method.
通过费德曼审讯法 他显露出说谎的特征
This is a method utilized by the police
这是一种警察采用的审讯方法
- to question suspects? - Yes.
- 用来审讯犯罪嫌疑人吗 - 是啊
And the plaintiff signed this confession?
然后原告就签了认罪状吗
Yes. He told us exactly how he...
是啊 他还供述了他是怎么把赃物装车
took them down to Maxwell Street Market,
如何带到街市上卖掉 并获利1万美元
- Thank you, Mr. Diyardian. - He gave me that information.
- 谢谢你 Diyardian先生 - 那些信息都是他告诉我的
- Nothing more here, Your Honor. - Mike,
- 那我没什么可问的了 法官大人 - Mike
could you angle that screen some more?
你能不能帮忙把屏幕往这边转一转
These sunglasses are polarized.
这墨镜是偏光的
Yeah, keep coming, keep coming. Ah.
对 再往这边转转
Keep coming, keep coming. Oh, well...
再转点 再转点 好吧
Uh, continue, please.
请接着说吧
Uh, just a few questions, Benji.
Benji 我想问几个问题
Why didn't you tell the police about the theft?
既然有盗窃案发生 你为什么不报警
Excuse me?
你说什么
Well, if it were me and I had $70,000 stolen,
如果是我被偷了7万美金
I would go to the police.
我肯定会报警
Well, the company would rather settle these things internally.
我们公司更想把这事内部解决了
And I'd rather you call me "Mr. Diyardian."
另外 请叫我Diyardian先生
Oh, my apologies.
抱歉
And Mr. Gwinn stole this $70,000,
经您审讯 Gwinn先生偷了那7万美金是吗
My interview.
我的询问
Right, your interview.
对 您的询问
To your mind, Frank Gwinn is a thief, right?
在您看来 Frank Gwinn是个贼 是吗
Well, he stole, yes.
是啊 他盗窃
Then why didn't the company fire him?
那公司为什么不炒了他
Your Honor, I-I think it's a little odd that BMI
法官大人 我认为BMI做出如此人道的处理
is being censured for doing the humanitarian thing.
反而受到责难实在说不过去
Oh, I don't think plaintiff is censuring them.
我倒没觉得原告在苛责BMI
I think she just finds it odd that they kept the thief on staff,
我觉得她就是奇怪为什么要留下一个贼
as do I.
我也挺好奇
Well, the company just wanted an opportunity
公司只是想弥补自己的损失 不是吗
Right, it did.
是啊
So the company wanted to keep Frank employed
所以公司仍旧聘用Frank
so they could take from his paycheck?
这样他们就可以用他的薪水补亏了
- Is that right? - Well, that's not how I'd put it.
- 对吗 - 我们不这么定义
How would you put it, Benji? Please take your time.
Benji 那你怎么说 请抓紧时间
You're suggesting bad motives here.
你暗示这其中存有不良动机
But BMI thinks all its employees
但是BMI认为
should be allowed to make things right.
它的每个员工都理应得到弥补过错的机会
And so, even though, Frank, supposedly stole $70,000,
那么尽管Frank可能偷了这7万美金
he was still allowed to work alone
他也仍可以独自在无人监管的库房工作吗
Objection. Asked and answered.
我反对 她这是自问自答
Uh, actually, no, I'd like to hear the answer.
实际上我挺想听听他如何回答
We trust our employees.
我相信我们的员工
And that's why you questioned him for seven hours?
那你为什么审讯他7小时之久呢
Objection. Argumentative.
我反对 这是争议问题
I'll rephrase. How many hours did you question my client?
我换种说法 你审讯了我的当事人多久
I don't know. I didn't keep track.
我不知道 我没计算
uh, it says seven hours here.
这里写着那 七个小时
Oh, hello, Lucca.
你好 Lucca
Good to see you're still at it.
很高兴看到你积极工作
And it's um...
啊 这是
Mai... I'm sorry, Mia.
Mai...抱歉 Mia
- Maia. - Maia, thank you.
- Maia - Maia 谢谢你
- Hi. I'm Andrea. - Hi.
- 你好 我是Andrea - 你好
I'm so terribly sorry about your family.
关于你家里的事 我很遗憾
Must be hard on you.
你一定很不容易吧
- It's manageable. - Manageable.
- 好在还可控 - 可控
Good.
挺好
Women are taking over the world, piece by piece.
女性正在一步步的掌控世界
Um, I'm wondering if you and I could talk sometime, Lucca.
有机会我能跟你谈谈吗 Lucca
We can talk right now.
现在就行啊
Well, I-I just
我不愿意在这种公共场合谈 但是
So, what's the offer?
那你们出价多少
Offer?
出价
No, I-I just wanted to know where you got your hair cut.
并不是 我就是想知道你头发是在哪剪的
I just, I love the bangs so much.
我就是 很喜欢你这刘海
A friend of mine.
我朋友剪的
- She cuts hair out of her apartment. - Really?
- 她在她自己的公寓里剪 - 真的吗
- Could you maybe get me her number? - Sure.
- 那你能把她电话给我吗 - 当然啦
Thank you.
谢谢你
Gosh. Mm.
天呐
I love this, by the way.
顺便说一句 我真喜欢你这项链
It would look great on you. Do you want to buy it?
要是你带上肯定好看 你想买吗
No.
并不
I'd sooner buy the smile off the Mona Lisa.
我倒是想买蒙娜丽莎脸上的微笑
See you tomorrow.
明天见
Bye, Mia.
再见 Mia
_
你妈妈来了
It was just was a scare.
就是疑似肿瘤
Dr. Trotter found another lump.
Trotter医生发现了另一个肿块
But he thinks it's nothing.
但他觉得应该没事
Good.
那就好
Is that why you called?
这就是你打电话给我的原因吗
Oh, yes, I mean, I was told the cancer
对 我听说你的癌症
had spread to your lymph nodes.
已经扩散到你的淋巴结了
Well, that's the fear.
是有这种担心
It's good to see you, Maia.
我很高兴见到你 Maia
You look older.
你看起来老了些
Look at me, Mom.
看着我 妈妈
Why?
怎么了
I just want to ask you a few questions.
我只想问你几个问题
Oh, Maia, I spent the last two weeks answering more questions
Maia 我这两个星期回答的问题
than I have in my whole life.
比我这辈子回答过的都多
Yes. And I am your daughter.
是 可我是你女儿
And I just want to ask you a few more.
我只想再问你几个
Look at me.
看着我
Okay, I'm looking at you.
好 我看着你呢
Was there really a cancer scare?
真的是疑似癌症复发吗
Yes, baby,
是的 宝贝
there was a cancer scare.
之前的确是疑似癌症复发
And you're not lying to me?
你没有在骗我
I'm your mother.
我是你妈妈
- Is Dad guilty? - You know he's not.
- 爸爸有罪吗 - 你知道他无罪的
Are you guilty?
那你有罪吗
No, Maia, I'm not guilty.
没有 Maia 我没罪
Uncle Jax is guilty.
Jax叔叔有罪
You just need to trust me, baby.
你需要相信我 宝贝
We're family.
我们是一家人
I don't know if she's lying or not.
我不知道她是不是在说谎
About the cancer?
撒关于癌症的谎吗
No, about the fund.
不是 是对基金的事情说谎
Do you think your dad did it?
你觉得是你爸爸干的吗
I don't know.
我不知道
We were always the boring family.
我们一直是个无聊的家庭
I mean, all my friends, their...
我的朋友们 他们
their parents were divorcing
他们的父母都忙着离婚
or having affairs and...
或者婚内出轨
I used to lie about Mom and Dad fighting,
我以前还骗人说我爸妈吵架
so that I wouldn't seem so weird.
好让我看起来不那么奇怪
And now...
而现在...
it's like we're paying for all those years of happiness.
像是我们在为那几年的幸福生活买单
That's your parents.
那是你父母在买单
Doesn't have to be you.
你不用这样
You can be as happy as you want.
你想怎么幸福都可以
And we're back.
我们继续
Now, here's the thing, young man.
现在 有个事儿 年轻人
No, you can all sit down.
不用 你们都坐着
I have a question for you.
我有个问题要问你
What is supination?
什么是旋后功能
I was buying running shoes yesterday
昨天我去买跑步鞋
and they told me my feet supinate?
售货员说我足后旋
Yeah, uh, supination
是 旋后功能
is when your feet roll outward when you run.
是指当你跑步时脚掌外翻
- Oh, and that's a bad thing? - Yes, it can be a bad thing.
- 这是个不好的动作吗 - 对 不好
But that's why you need shoes with a firmer outer sole.
所以你需要买外底坚固的跑鞋
- Ah. Shoes like these? - Uh,
- 像这种吗 - 呃
Your Honor, um,
法官大人
we do have a witness,
我们有一位证人
but if you're feeling biased towards the plaintiff,
但如果你更偏向于原告
we ask that we be heard on a recusal.
那我们可能需要需要您回避了
No, no. No, counselor.
不 辩方律师
I'm just getting some advice.
我只是在寻求建议
My apologies.
我道歉
I will work hard toward neither supinating
我努力既不旋后
nor pronating toward one side or the other.
也不旋前 不偏倚任何一边
Your next witness.
你的下一位证人
The interviewer merely tries to ease the way
询问者只是用更简单的方法
for a liar to admit the truth, that's all.
让骗子说出事实 仅此而已
So you tend to minimize the crime?
所以你想尽可能地减少犯罪
Yes.
对
According to Mr. Diyardian's own testimony,
Diyardian先生自己的证词
he made it clear to the suspect
他很明确地告诉嫌疑人
that the theft was not a big matter.
偷窃不是件大事
They just wanted to solve it.
他们只是想解决问题
In fact, he could understand why someone would be tempted.
事实上 他明白为什么有的人会被诱惑
He was even tempted.
他也有相同困扰
And the plaintiff has suggested
而且原告还说到
that Mr. Diyardian handed all the details
Diyardian掌握了全部关于Gwinn先生
of the flea market sale to Mr. Gwinn?
在跳蚤市场卖鞋的所有细节
Yes, but that's just part of our method.
对 这是我们的方法之一
Making it clear to the suspect
让嫌疑人清楚
that you know all the particulars of his crime
你知道你犯罪的所有准确细节
helps him feel there is no way to avoid detection.
让他明白无论如何都逃不掉调查
And this is the same method used by police
而且警察也是这么做的
- to catch criminals? - Yes, definitely.
- 去抓犯罪分子吗 - 是 当然了
It is tried and tested.
经过反复实验与实践
All done here, Your Honor.
我问完了 法官大人
Do you want to do it?
你想去盘问吗
- Well, if you don't want to. - No. No.
- 如果你不想去的话 - 不 不
I want to.
我想去
Mr. Le Frenais.
Le Frenais先生
La Frenais.
是La Frenais
Is it part of your method
你的某些方法
that you can lie to the suspect?
是不是对嫌疑人说谎
Sorry, Counselor. You, uh... can you speak up?
不好意思 辩方律师 能不能说话大点声
I think that Lisa is having problems hearing you.
我觉得Lisa听不清你说什么
Yes. Of course.
那好的
Is it part of your Friedman method, sir,
先生 你的弗里德曼法
that you can lie to the suspect being questioned?
是不是在对被提问的嫌疑人说谎
Whoa. Much better, thank you.
哇 好多了 谢谢你
It's not part of my method.
这不是我的方法
It's part of the Supreme Court decision, Frazier v. Cupp.
是最高法院的裁决 Frazier对Cupp的案子
Police officers can lie to suspects.
警官可以对嫌疑人说谎
And so in step number five of your method,
所以在你的方法的第五步
the interviewer is to present
询问人会提供很多
evidence of culpability to the suspect,
有罪证据给嫌疑人
whether it's true or not?
不管这些证据是不是真的
Well, it's better if the evidence is true, of course.
当然 如果证据刚好是真的
But it doesn't have to be?
但也不一定是真实证据
No.
不一定
So when Benji presented Frank
所以当Benji呈现给Frank
with a DVD recording of him stealing
一张他正在偷窃
the $70,000 in running shoes...
7万美金的跑鞋的DVD时
a DVD that was completely blank, by the way...
顺便说一下 这是张完全空白的DVD
that was A-okay with you?
这对你来说也是可行的吗
Yes,
是的
if it helps find a crook, yes.
如果这对抓贼有用的话 是可行的
But doesn't your method result in false confessions?
难道你的方法不会导致错误的认罪吗
Very few.
非常少
In fact, hasn't your method
事实上 你的方法
been banned by police
难道不是被
in Canada and England?
加拿大和英格兰警方禁用了吗
I wouldn't call it banned. They've chosen not to use it.
我认为那不是禁用 是他们选择不用
Oh, because it resulted in too many false confessions?
是因为这方法导致太多错误的认罪吗
I don't think that's fair.
我认为这不公正
But is it true, sir?
但这是真的吗 先生
I'll leave that analysis to others.
我留予他人评说
Analysis. What...
评说 什么
"The Friedman Method
“弗里德曼法”
"is a banned coercive technique of interrogation
“是被强制禁用的审讯方法”
"that results in too many false confessions.
“因为其导致了众多错误的认罪”
"It is therefore banned within our jurisdiction."
“因此在我们所辖区域禁止使用”
Do you mean analysis like that?
你是指这样的评说吗
Who wrote that?
那是谁写的
Melissa Starr.
Melissa Starr
London Metropolitan Police. Scotland Yard.
伦敦市警方 苏格兰警场
Okay.
好的
Uh...
呃
anything further?
还有其他的吗
Nothing here, Your Honor.
没有了 法官大人
Thank you.
谢谢您
Hi. This is Diane Lockhart's office,
嗨 这是Diane Lockhart的办公室吗
and I'm her assistant, Marissa. How may I help you?
我是她的助理Marissa 有什么需要帮忙的吗
It's Dr. Ainsworth at Harbor Hospital.
是港口医院Ainsworth医生的电话
- Do you want to call him back? - Please.
- 你打算一会儿给他回电话吗 - 好的
Diane.
Diane
You didn't like any of the applicants?
你不喜欢其他的应聘者吗
Oh, for the assistant's job?
哦 那个助理工作
Uh, no, I did. It's just that I know Marissa,
我挺喜欢的 只是我了解Marissa
and she's on the ball. She's good.
她很聪明的 她很不错
You'll see.
你以后就明白了
Okay. This is our offer.
好吧 这是我们给的报价
$500,000 to Frank Gwinn.
给Frank Gwinn的五十万美金
No class action.
不能提出集体诉讼
If the firm pursues a class action,
如果你们律所提出集体诉讼
our offer goes away and Frank gets nothing.
我们的报价也没了 Frank什么也得不到
Lot of money for a guy pulling in 40 grand a year.
这对于一个一年只挣四万的人来说是很多钱了
Mm-hmm.
嗯
What do you think of that, Maia?
你觉得呢 Maia
I think we'll have to get back to you.
我们会再联系你的
Okay.
好的
In the next, uh, two hours,
那两个小时后给我答案
or we go back to court, and destroy you.
否则就回法庭 毁了你
- Ms. Stevens. - Yeah.
- Stevens女士 - 什么事
I have an answer for you now.
我现在就有个答案给你
Oh. Great.
太好了
My hair stylist's number.
这是我发型师的电话
Well?
所以呢
We got a decision to make.
我们需要做个决定
No. It's not enough money for us to take.
不行 我们没什么钱可赚
It's not your decision. It's the client's.
这不是你们说了算 是客户说了算
No. It's a decision for the whole class:
不 这是为集体做出的决定
all 24 clients.
为24个客户考虑
The algorithm says we stay in.
这个算法让我们跟进
This is crazy.
这太扯了
You can't have them decide what we do.
你不能用算法程序来决定我们的事情
They're paying the bills, Lucca.
这个算法可在帮着挣钱呢 Lucca
Yes, but Frank needs the money.
是的 但Frank需要这笔钱
If we pass on this, he could get nothing.
如果我们不接这个报价 他什么都得不到
Or he could get a whole lot more.
或者他能得到更多钱
Let's just wait and see.
我们拭目以待
I just have one last question for you, Frank.
我最后还有一个问题 Frank
Why did you confess?
你为什么认罪
If you didn't do it, then why would you confess?
如果你什么都没做 那为什么认罪
He made it seem like it was the only way out.
他说得好像认罪是唯一的出路
He he had a DVD of me doing it.
他有一张我偷窃的DVD
And if you knew there was nothing on that DVD,
如果你知道DVD里什么都没有
then why would you confess?
那你问什么要认罪
I felt helpless. I was exhausted.
我觉得很无助 我筋疲力尽了
He had me convinced that I just repressed the memory.
他说服我说那是段被抑制的记忆
He said he had a witness who swore
他说他有一个发过誓的证人
that I was down at a flea market, selling the shoes.
说我在跳蚤市场卖鞋
- Were you? - No.
- 你做过吗 - 没有
But he said he was gonna give all this to the cops
但他说他要把这些证据交给警察
if I didn't come clean to the company.
如果我不向公司坦白
Come clean, meaning?
坦白 意味着
Sign this statement that he wrote up.
在他写的那张纸上签字
- And so you signed it? - Yes.
- 所以你签了吗 - 签了
He said that I could keep my job,
他说我可以保住我的工作
he said that the questioning would be over.
他说询问就会结束
He said that I would still be on management track.
他说我还会留在管理层
Did you know that Benji gets a bonus
你知不知道Benji每捉到一个
for every employee he gets to confess?
认罪的人都会得到奖金
Objection. No foundation.
反对 无依据
Uh, that is definitely sustained.
这肯定反对有效
Okay, um, I think
好吧 我看
I'm ready to rule on this motion.
我已经可以裁决了
Uh, Your Honor, I'd like to cross-examine.
法官大人 我想进行交叉询问
This is not a full trial.
这不是个审判庭
This is merely a motion to dismiss.
只不过是个动议撤销庭
Yeah, I know, but this information just came into our hands.
对 我知道 只是我刚拿到这个线索
We were hoping to use it at trial, but...
我们本想拿到庭上
we think we can save the court a lot of time and money
但为了给法庭省时省钱
if we could ask it now.
我们决定现在就问
- I... am enticed. - Thank you, Your Honor.
- 我 我被你说服了 - 谢谢您 法官大人
Mr. Gwinn, where did you work before BMI?
Gwinn先生 你在来BMI之前在哪儿工作
Various places. I worked as a temp.
好多地方 都是兼职
And was one these places Tolleson Accounting?
是否有其中一家公司叫Tolleson会计事务所
- Yes. - You had a clerical job there?
- 对 - 你在那儿做书记员
Uh-huh.
嗯哼
I'll take that as a yes.
我就当你说的是
And were you asked to leave?
你是否被辞退了
- I didn't do it. - Yeah.
- 我什么都没做 - 对
I think you know what's coming, Frank.
我猜你知道会发生什么 Frank
There was a petty cash situation,
当时有个小额现金丢失状况
several hundred dollars?
也就几百美金
And were you accused of taking it?
你被指控偷了这些钱 对吗
I told them I didn't take it.
我说了我没拿
But you agreed to leave
但你同意离职
if they didn't call the cops?
如果他们不报警的话
Objection, there is no record of this.
反对 没有证据
Our investigators questioned this business.
我们的调查员了解了此事
Yes, because the manager at the time
对 因为这个经理
talked only to our investigator,
只向我们的调查员说了此事
and signed this affidavit.
并且签了书面保证
I didn't do it.
我没有拿
In it, he swears that Frank took the money,
在保证书里他发誓Frank拿了钱
then when he was caught, promised to return it
当他被发现时 同意归还
if they kept the theft secret.
如果他们对这起盗窃密而不发
That's a lie!
这是说谎
That's a complete and total lie.
这完全是说谎
Okay. That is information
好的 这则信息
I will take into consideration.
我会考虑的
Does the defendant have any more questions?
被告还有别的问题吗
Nothing more, Your Honor.
没有了 法官大人
Unless the plaintiff has anything more,
除非原告还有问题
I will rule on this motion.
我将做出判决
I hate losing.
我讨厌输
It was a good effort.
至少努力过了
Does this impact the class?
这对集体诉讼有影响吗
Yes, unfortunately.
很不幸 是的
The litigation financiers dropped out.
诉讼赞助人撤了
I thought he was telling the truth.
我以为他说的是真话
Well, maybe he was.
也许他说的是真话
About the running shoes.
关于跑鞋的事儿
You know, people can lie and still be telling the truth.
你知道吗 有的人可以撒谎的同时说真话
Nobody's a hundred percent of any one thing.
没有人在某件事上百分之百真实的
My mom lied about her cancer.
我妈妈有癌症的事儿是假的
It was a scare. It wasn't real.
只是疑似 不是真的
She just wanted to see me.
她只是想见我
She's lonely.
她很孤单
People get desperate when they're lonely.
人们在孤单的时候会感到绝望
You should go see her.
你应该去看看她
Mom?
妈妈
Maia, what are you doing?
Maia 你来干什么
I wanted to see how you were.
我想来看看你怎么样了
Good. I was just going to bed.
我很好 我准备睡觉了
What's wrong?
怎么了
Why don't we have breakfast tomorrow?
要不我们明天一起吃早餐
Whose car is that outside?
外面是谁的车
Just the painters were here yesterday. They left one.
昨天油漆工来了 把车落下了
Where's the tea, Lenore?
茶在哪儿呢 Lenore
It's not a good time.
现在不是时候
Hi, Uncle Jax.
嗨 Jax叔叔
Synced and corrected by Aaronnmb www.addic7ed.com
-------------------------- 本论坛字幕仅翻译交流学习之用 禁止任何商业用途否则后果自负 --------------------------